actblue.com 2019-12-21

# ActBlue — privacy

## Privacy Policy

This privacy policy describes how we use your personal information. As used in this policy, the term “personal information” means information that can be directly associated with an individual and includes names, addresses, telephone numbers, email addresses, etc. 

### E-mail addresses

We require your email address when you donate so that we can email you a receipt. We may add your email address to our email list where we send email updates and requests for donations. You can unsubscribe at any time by clicking [here](https://actblue.actionkit.com/cms/unsubscribe/unsubscribe/). If you are having problems with this link, you can unsubscribe by e-mailing [info@actblue.com](mailto:info@actblue.com), but please allow a week for processing. 

### Information Collected by ActBlue

When you contribute to candidates, causes, and committees on ActBlue, we collect your **name, postal address, phone number, email address, occupation, employer, and, in some cases, employer's address,** depending on the type of contribution you’re making. Campaign finance law requires that we send your name, address, occupation, and employer information along with details of your donation to the recipient of your contribution and report this information in our reports to the Federal Election Commission (FEC) or the relevant respective state agency. Each candidate, committee, or organization receiving your donations may also include this information in their regulatory reports. FEC reports containing this information are publicly available from the [FEC website](http://www.fec.gov/). State reports are typically available through the state agency designated to oversee campaigns and elections. ActBlue does not publicly report your personal information in connection with your charitable or social welfare giving. 

### Credit Card Information

We securely transmit your credit card information to one of our payment processors: Vantiv WorldPay, PayPal, or Apple Pay. We do not store this information unless you have specifically requested us to store it for ease of future payments with an ActBlue Express account or for a recurring contribution. All credit card information is handled in accordance with current PCI standards. ActBlue is a PCI Level 1 service provider. 

### Reports to contribution form creators

People who create contribution forms receive reports about donations made through the forms they made. These reports include the dates, amounts, and recipients of contributions as well as the names, addresses, email addresses, and phone numbers of donors. 

### Use of third party vendors

Payment processing on ActBlue.com is provided by Vantiv WorldPay, PayPal, and Apple Pay. ActBlue may share your personal data with these and other third parties in connection with the processing of your contributions or other services we offer. Any such third parties shall be required to maintain and use your information in accordance with our privacy policy. Personal information may be shared between the various legal entities that make up ActBlue for ActBlue's purposes alone. 

Other than as described above, we will not use your personal information nor release it to any other party without your permission, unless we believe it is necessary to share information in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, violations of our terms of use, or as otherwise required by law. In such cases, we will use or share only as much of your personal information as is required for this purpose. 

### Cookies

Some parts of the ActBlue site use cookies. A “cookie” is a tiny text file that is stored on your computer and enables you to return to password-protected areas on our website without having to re-enter your password. We also facilitate cookies for tracking systems such as Google ads. You can disable these cookies by modifying your web browser preferences. 

### IP Addresses

We log IP addresses, which are the locations of computers or networks on the Internet, and analyze them for systems administration and troubleshooting purposes. We also aggregate the number of page hits in order to track the popularity of certain pages and improve the quality of our site. 

### Children

ActBlue does not knowingly solicit or collect personally identifying information from children under the age of 13. ActBlue does not permit contributions from minors under the age of 18. 

Questions? Contact us.
